Heather Samsel

Email: hsshop1@gmail.com | Phone: 215-493-3869 | Yardley, PA 19067

Github: https://github.com/savycodr | LinkedIn: https://github.com/savycodr | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/heather-samsel

Website: https://savycodr.github.io/portfolio

PROFESSIONAL TITLE

Full Stack Web Developer with a background in architecture, engineering, and software development. Able to build sophisticated websites with full database backend from mockup to rollout. Continually increasing knowledge and experience by keeping abreast of evolving trends, techniques, and technologies to improve efficiency. Adept at working with diverse teams to implement projects.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Java, UML

Applications: Github, Heroku, JQuery, React, Bootstrap, Materialize, Handlebars, Firebase, MySQL, Sequelize, MongoDB, Mongoose, Node, Express, Socket.io, Passport, Postman, Zoom,

Linter, Mocha, Chai

EDUCATION

University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA

Certificate, Full Stack Web Development

Intensive 24-week certification dedicated to designing and building web applications.

Washington University, St. Louis, MO

Master of Science, Mechanical Engineering

Parks College of St. Louis University, St. Louis, MO

Bachelor of Science, Aerospace Engineering

St. Louis University, St. Louis, MO

Bachelor of Arts, Physics

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer 2000- 2002

Open Tout (formarks Usumming bird Communications)

Tallabasson Fl.

OpenText (formerly Hummingbird Communications)

Tallahassee, FL

Designed, coded, and tested commercial Java software for document control and storage.

- Introduced and directed UML for projects
- Created architecture for testing, revision control, and builds

Senior Analyst 1999-2000

Wells Fargo Advisors (formerly A. G. Edwards)

St. Louis, MO

Java mentor and technical lead for web based financial software. Consultant for best practices and integration with the enterprise infrastructure. Collaborated with business users to create software specifications. Effectively communicated design to developers using UML.

Senior Engineer 1996-1999

The Boeing Company

St. Louis, MO

Developed architecture to connect Java client interfaces with legacy software. Wrote code for application running structural analysis on virtual aircraft designs.

• Selected to represent Boeing on structural engineering team sent to Kuala Lumpur

Engineer, Advanced Design

1993-1996

Lockheed Martin Aeronautical Systems

St. Louis, MO

Developed software used for conceptualizing 3-D aircraft designs and analyzing capabilities. Wrote and presented aircraft design reviews to senior leadership. Created software to aid in the wiring design of the F-22 Raptor and the C-130J Hercules.

- Selected for the F-35 Joint Strike Fighter design team
- Aircraft designs were published in Aviation Week and Space Technology

ADDITIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

Vice President 2018-present

Makefield Women's Association

Lower Makefield, PA

Coordinate volunteer services at the homeless shelter. Raise funds for beneficiaries. Set and approve budget as a member of the finance committee.

• Member since 2015

PROJECTS

Coaster Catalog, MERN App | Link to Github | Link to deployed site

Full Stack MERN app enables users to rate roller coasters and keep track of their rides. A showcase for user sessions and authentication.

• Languages and technologies used: Javascript, JQuery, Mongoose, MongoDB, React, Passport, Bootstrap

Burger Restaurant, Full Stack App | Link to Github | Link to deployed site

Full Stack burger creation app. Persists to MySQL database.

Languages and technologies used: Javascript, JQuery, Sequelize, Handlebars, Bootstrap